Jon Christie

(919) 368-3369 • fullstack11235@gmail.com • www.jonchristie.io

OBJECTIVE

Coding Instructor for Varsity Tutors and professional web developer with over 5 years experience in web development and following 11 years in education. Front end, back end, and full stack web development using various stacks for different uses like data analysis or eCommerce apps. Ongoing drive to learn and adapt using a set of crucial natural talents have made me an irreplaceable asset for the companies and people I've had the pleasure working over the years. As a coding instructor, I've kept me up to date with the industry, in touch with new connections and opportunities, and continue to expand my knowledge. Helping and teaching young adults how to take their next step in life for 9-10 years keeps one quite mindful of those very skills being passed along. Active listening, adaptability, communication, confidence, creativity, patience, problem solving, teamwork, time management, humor, and fun are some additional skills I practice, value, and happily share.

SKILLS

LANGUAGES

• HTML	• CSS	Javascript	Python
 Angular 	 TypeScript 		
FRAMEWORKS, LIBRARIES, AND ENVIRONMENTS			
• React	• Express	Bootstrap	NodeJS
 MaterialUI 	• ThreeJS	• D3	NextJS
 TailwindCSS 			
SYSTEMS, CMS, & DATABASES			
• Git	• CLI	 MySQL 	• HTTP
 GraphQL 	 Google Cloud Platform 	MongoDB	 Cloud DBaaS
• REST	• APIs	 Amazon Web Services 	 Agile Methods
TESTING			
 React Testing Library 	• Jest	Mocha	Jasmine
• Chai	 Lambda Test 		
OTHER SOFTWARE + SKILLS			
• SEO	 Quantitative analysis 	 Responsive Web Design 	 Functional Programming
 Object Oriented Programming 	Adobe CS	• Figma	Unity 3D

PROJECTS

• Blender

Super Pantry Buddy, 2020

- **Live Site:** https://superpantrybuddy.herokuapp.com/
- GitHub Repository: https://github.com/mathcodes/SuperPantryBuddy

Logic Pro X

- Technology: React, React ContextMongoDB, Node, ORM, Express, OAuth, Jest, Bulma, Figma
- Description: MERN stack- Responsive, customizable user experience to find and save recipes. I personally implemented authhorization, State, and testing. Future development includes improving UI and utilizing more data from the API.

• Audio Production

A Python Log, 2021

- **Live Site:** https://jonspythonlog.herokuapp.com/
- GitHub Repository: https://github.com/mathcodes/PythonLog/
- Technology: Python, CSS, HTML, JS, Replit, Django, Tkinter, JSON, Illustrator
- Description: A full stack blog using Python in the backend. Users post, share, and delete content using HTTP Requests and CRUD conventions. A mobile-friendly design adds functionality with a responsive UI.

Sweet Clover Barn, 2020-2022

- Live Site: www.sweetcloverbarn.com
- **Technology:** HTML, CSS, SquareSpace
- Description: This was my first solo freelance opportunity and opportunity to put my SEO knowledge to the test. Based on the clients' needs, I updated the UI with a modern look, and added an online store, sign-up, and application forms, and implemented SEO strategies which tripled non-branded traffic and increased sales by 213%.

Jon Christie

(919) 368-3369 • fullstack11235@gmail.com • www.jonchristie.io

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Varsity Tutors – Coding Instructor

- Remote 2021 present
- Maintained a 100% success rate with both student retention and feedback, all 5/5 and written by students of all ages
 each week, verifying the quality of my services and knowledge of the material
- Led presentations to up to 100 listeners at a time covering HTML, JS, CSS, Express, Node, MongoDB, React while fielding questions from the viewers with a cumulative 94% successful review rating.
- Created and implemented various lessons plans covering several different learning strategies for mastering code amounting to 20-30 hours of work per week on top of research, projects, and tutoring sessions
- Inspired and motivated students using my knowledge and love for over 20 in-demand coding languages and technologies including Javascript, HTML, CSS, Jquery, Python, OOP, React, C++, AWS Cloud Services, Java, and Angular

Pivotous - Reputation Manager / Web Developer

- Remote 2020 2021
- Organized and oversaw a team of 11 Technical Assistants by training them on software to track and monitor progress
 using data analytics and up-to-date SEO tactics
- Enhanced competitive analysis using CHAIN and C&RT models to optimize clients' ROI effectively by more than 23%.
- Monitored, restored, and enhanced software updates using marketing software to serve clients at scale
- Expedited and refined marketing strategies using customized software to increase clientele by an average of 178.8%
- Managed team of 30+ successful WPP Brand Account Managers, Media Negotiators and Promotions Specialists

TE21, Inc – EdTech Developer

Durham, NC 2016 - 2018

- Introduced and implemented Python, MathML, LaTeX, HTML, CSS, and JS for entire company's 5-person curricular teams
 to increase the rate of digitizing 80,000 test items by 7.2 times the original rate to integrate our items into the new Certica
 platform while maintaining mobile-responsive items.
- Introduced a new industry-wide EdTech feature: customizable test items by state standards while providing an easy-to-use item creator for teachers to create their own items that mirror the End-Of-Course testing functionality.
- Collaborated with Certica techs and formed a team to execute the merging of a total of more than 220,000 test items, each an object with over 50 parameters utilized to implement entity resolution, Machine Learning, and data matching processes to sort and parse the items as needed.

PACE Academy High School, Mathematics Teacher

Carrboro, NC 2006 - 2016

- Increased the Math Department's EOC score from 0% to 100% first year, "Teacher of the Year" 2006-2007
- Managed the Math Department all 8 years and met every budget while bringing technology to my students' daily exercises to maintain a career-long passing rate of 94.3%.
- Adapted to a new environment as a leader quickly and developed strong relationships with co-workers and students
 alike, forming a leadership role which led to years of producing and executing school-wide events, projects, competitions,
 field trips, fund-raisers, and community-based development and events.

EDUCATION

AWS Certified Developer – Associate (DVA-C01) – exam scheduledJune 2022University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, Full-Stack Certificate Program2020Web Developer Certificate – Durham Tech, IT Web Developer Certificate2011University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, BA Mathematics2001 – 2005